[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
[Music]
at what age should we learn to have
better conversations with ourselves
[Music]
knowledge is power
reality is that just get two hours later
we're like oh so man I've got it I have
a I've deleted podcast episodes multiple
episodes I've deleted entirely uh I've
forgot to hit record like until I was 20
minutes or so in more than once uh I've
I've fudged it
[Laughter]
some of my best ones or I guess
uh some of the better ones yeah they
have had like either like major
technical issues like someone drops out
halfway through and you don't know until
editing or
they just vanish like you ever had to
file just vanish you're like where where
did it go
yeah I have a ton
um frustrated like I feel like my
computer sometimes deletes things
without my permission it happens with
tracks all the time too
um yeah or I will that sucks I like to
record my audio separate in um in my Daw
I like I use Ableton so I record it in
there just so I can edit it later and
make it sound fancy and I had a ton of
them that just like all of the files
that I recorded got deleted I mean I had
the zoom back up so I was able to use it
but I still really don't know what I did
to delete a ton of my own recordings
from podcasts
oh man dude I have Ableton Live
and I have never opened it it's daunting
dude it is so intimidating it's a
staircase
just looking at it I'm like I don't even
want to open I'm just gonna leave you
you look pretty on the desktop that's
about it yeah and you could tell people
you have it like yeah yeah I got Ableton
Live no big deal so it's actually my
main weapon I still I mean there's so I
still suck at it I think um I've been
using it it's been my main thing for a
long time but luckily I had the
ignorance as Bliss I didn't realize that
it was like like super difficult to
start on it was just one that I had
heard of when I first started thinking
music is cool to try to make
um and I was like all right well that's
the one I had a friend help me out and
like you know crack it
um and just started cracking on it and
just because I've been forced to use it
and using it so much I kind of know my
way around it but yeah it's a I mean I
don't know that I could teach anybody
how to use it yeah you have well that's
really cool that's gonna uh and I mean
the tracks you sent me like that have
that specific style that's like almost
like this beat poetry
um like train tracky beat poetry Vibe
with like
the like just generally has like this
calm meditative uh Trail to it I feel
like that's the best way man because
like I myself have I taught myself
guitar
um and like I specifically was a very
much a hard ass about never learning any
covers or any other songs or whatever
like and so but what that does is when
you when you get into it and you just
dig deep in the in the mystery of music
you develop your own style and you know
it though it takes a very very very long
time longer than you know being
classically trained and learning theory
and scales and everything you still get
to envelop your own truth through the
music
um and through that time and that you
put in that hard work and so it's it is
quite quite a journey and uh that's
impressive man to teach yourself Ableton
like that is no small feat you know you
put that on your gravestone yeah bro you
YouTube is is my BFF too for sure like I
spent a lot of time on YouTube and just
trying [__] and again like I still I
feel like I I if I had somebody who was
really good at Ableton over my shoulder
I'd be like yeah I kind of know Ableton
like I feel like I wouldn't be very
sturdy like I wouldn't say it with my
chest like yeah I know able to you know
just because there's so many layers like
did the people who are good at that
program are good at that program really
all of these programs are like there's
levels too I can work my way around and
I can make some [__] sound like cool and
and I can figure out how to get your mic
or get your vocals over some tracks and
stuff but there's there's levels to it
bro uh hey also I was thinking about
when you were just saying like going
through the route of learning music you
know in the non-traditional way not only
like not reading music but like kind of
just teaching and like falling into it
and just like the hours of listening to
yourself sound so bad like trying to
find occasionally sound good like was
that was that a process for you of like
like getting through the frustrating
part of I know there's something good in
here so just keep fiddling around and
yeah I mean you you know me I mean so
for people that don't know we we uh
we've known each other for a very long
time since since the high school days
yeah and um I've always been kind of
just like a
a little bit of a fringe weirdo on the
on the social groups and things you know
I'm like I kind of fit in here kind of
fit in there but it's always a always
just been a little weird so I liked
weird things and so to me though they
might have sounded cool when I would
play for other people uh it would just
kind of like the timing and the Rhythm
wasn't something that was like what you
would consider to be catchy
um it's not your fault on the floor that
everybody's used to exactly and like you
know for me being such a hard ass and
growing up really loving punk music and
wanting just to be different like I've
always really
you know and we all strive for that
uniqueness or that that difference
um but you know when I when I was
growing up I was just like I
you know like sometimes it was in the
Forefront of my mind like I need to be a
crazy son of a [__] I need to be crazy
I need to be I need to be wild like I
feel like I need to be wild
and so you know but as you get older
it's just like
you know that little bit of that
youthful Spirit you know it lingers in
the back and you're like oh I don't know
if I should follow it and it's like
weird you do feel this this uh the the
youth and and the growing up like kind
of getting farther apart
um so I'm trying to hold on to that with
like all of my might
yeah isn't it such an art to hold on to
it and like try to decide how much like
do I keep a little Peter Pan in me do I
do I yes I'll tighten my you know shirt
and tie but I'm gonna throw my denim
jacket over it you know what I mean like
yeah yeah because you you certainly have
had that um like you know punk rock vibe
to you like edge of everything I feel
like you were certainly so I saw you as
someone who was like friends with
absolutely everybody like you were just
everybody got along with you everybody
had something nice to say about you I
feel like you were such a chameleon in
that way
it's definitely chameleony uh and like
the the truth about it all at the end of
the day is that like I'm a I'm a big I'm
a big loner because I'm a Scorpio and
like I didn't really fully embrace my
Scorpio archetype Scorpios for days but
we really enjoy our alone time and being
underneath our Rock and our shade and
low lighting we like low lighting we
like ambient lighting we like Vibes we
like chill
um and so you know it's funny because
like generally you know we don't
notice these archetypes unless you're
like you know completely raised by some
Mystic hippie uh Voodoo parents but uh
you know like you'll you'll notice that
when you look back at your youth you're
like oh my God I'm fulfilling these
these archetypes that like I've always
had because your Celestial chart has
always been a part of you and as you go
through the process so like if you start
to understand astrology now and then
look back at what you're doing as your
youth you find that you're fulfilling
those archetypal roles like even as a
youth so
um I definitely got along with everybody
I really like I like you know I've never
really gotten a lot of confrontations
like the most confrontations were like
you know some of the [__] I clung
myself to like my one of my best friends
were shot you know he was always getting
in conversations I was like so I guess
I'm getting in complications with this
guy as well
yeah yeah dude that's our path sometimes
that's that's how it is I mean I I I I
love all of my my friendships that I had
in that way where it's like at that time
that was exactly like what I needed and
I love that person to death but it's so
interesting and fun and cool to like see
yourself now and go like oh I was like
working out this thing that like of
course I was working out you know of
course I was going through that that
process yeah that's wild
so have you been I mean you just started
to mention astrology and stuff like we
haven't even got it for anybody
listening we haven't really got a chance
to catch up that much man I would like
we haven't hung out since high school
it's been we graduated in 2010 so I mean
it's been a grip so bro can you like
this is the most impossible thing but
can you give me like a what have you
been up to for the last you know decade
or whatever 13 years yeah oh [__] okay
um yeah I mean like we have time too so
like dive into like what what are you
into nowadays what do you love doing
like all victim you know oh my goodness
so
um Jake and I've rekindled because we
both have podcasts now and so you know
that was a really great way for us to
just be like hey you want to hang out
like yeah on the internet that's what
Millennials do now I'm a grown man
Millennials do this kind of [__]
oh my god
um but yeah I mean it dude it's been a
slow process man it's been a slow
process
um
I
I originally like out of high school
like I wanted to go to The Cordon Bleu
and be a chef like that's what I signed
up for my senior year of high school
food has always been a passion of mine I
even have Chef tattooed on my hands
food is an art flavor and community of
like feeding people is always rung true
like I love it
um I I I love the aspect of people
getting together of friend meals like I
cook for everybody all the time I go
home it's not Grandma cooking holiday
meals it's your boy you know but the
thing is is actually I met a medical I
met a girl uh so I'll give people a
little bit more insight so came to Kelso
High School right like switched senior
year from this other school in our town
to go to this other bigger school
because me and my friend were fed up
with like the Bold the the bull hungry
over at this other schools we're like
let's go transfer to Kelso where the
people are cooler and like you know see
what's up and I found myself uh actually
dating this incredibly beautiful woman I
was incredibly out of my league and you
know she was really popular in all these
things and uh this was Raquel uh Raquel
flowers who is just I love her to death
but man you know she is just she is wild
bro and then I I fell in love with
somebody who you would almost consider
it the complete polar opposite end with
this her name is Rebecca and she was the
like the most one of the most emo girls
in the entire
school right like she got caught like
you know slitting her wrist in the
bathroom like hanging out with the
prominently really hardcore gay dude
like she was you know so going from this
uh you know from this realm to this
realm where we were just completely
enveloped in Emotion that's where I
found myself
being able to feel more truly who I was
because I'm in you know like Scorpios
we're deep deep emotion like we want to
get to the real grit I'm not talking
like happy sad I'm talking like dark
blood like you know in a cavern on the
ground in the forest like just the the
true true heartbeat of Life The Shadow
side of life and
um so we fell in deep love and we dated
for about three and a half years and she
uh was going up to uh Western Washington
University and I was like well I already
have applied and signed up and got all
my grants worked out for Chef's school
but I guess I'm just gonna throw all
that in the wind and and go with you up
to here and then I started to dive
incredibly deep into psychedelics and
started having um that's where I had my
first Out of Body Experience
and this out of body experience was I
was walking on the street in Bellingham
Washington it was winter time you know
half an hour away from the Canadian
border incredibly cold and I had my
spirit
I like I had to lay down like on the
ground I just remember like looking up
and I had my spirit leave and go out to
what I what you would consider to be the
atmosphere it was the outside of the
atmosphere and I was just like a blue
energy I was like a blue light and I was
just nestled up what else was this this
was you know what this was like actually
a culmination of a couple things
um it is Bellingham I get you yeah yeah
yeah
it is a wild town and I have stories
about that town all day uh and it was
like it was actually an amalgamation of
uh
you know acid LSD but really it's like
do we even know
if it's that you know yeah and and you
know it is it's not it's like the
substance doesn't contain the experience
you know it's it's it's you know I mean
I like how you just animated that as
well that was beautiful yeah clip that
Jamie
um I'm sorry carry on uh yes okay so
you're you're above your body this is
fascinating I love this I love like any
sort of out of body near-death
experience oh man and it it really it
took me a while to digest this too
because I don't even think when I came
back into it I don't even think I
remembered it for like months
um but so basically what it was it was
like me going and being there and I
wasn't in my body I was the light in the
blue I was the blue body just like
everyone else around me was and when I
went up there I just remember like
touching proverbial blue energetic
elbows with each other and I was just
like
oh like where are we
here down there and I was like whoa and
it lasted two seconds and then I went I
went straight back in and then
here was and so it was just like you
know after leaving home and then just
being bombarded with these mind-opening
mind-altering experiences while also
being in an incredibly codependent
relationship
um was like learning so much about
about relationships in general like and
I think that's been a huge part for me
like you know because I've always been
in like these like really deep
relationships but I'm an introspective
kind of guy we're all like you know I'm
not afraid to
to to ask you know the hard questions
and to be like is this Eve right like
should I be in this like am I going to
force myself to be in this relationship
even though I know deep down that I I I
don't want to be or like it's halting me
in some way like it's halting my
progression
and so I had to leave and shortly after
leaving there after dropping out of
school which I only like
mildly regret at this point how old are
you about at this age but by now
um I had left I'm just about I'm uh in
between 19 and 20. uh I think 20 and
then I go move down to Portland where I
started this
wanted to be like stand-up comedy so I
did some stand-up I started writing
jokes
um I started getting into some short
films I had
about three short films that I'd done
and I was about to get my Screen Actors
Guild and
um I got this roll I got this role it
was a paid gig it was a good gig and I
was so excited that I went on to
Facebook and I nailed the audition I got
the call back I got the gig right I get
on Facebook I'm just like oh what up
everybody I'm so excited I got this you
know I got my first paid roll whatever
and the director was actually on
Facebook
and she sees it and she's just like what
the [__] is wrong with you you're
pre-production you're not supposed to
say anything because it was about a
short story and I like shared the short
story that the the film was going to be
about and she blew up on me and she was
just like she's like you'll never work
in this town again and I was like what I
was excited look I'm just excited I'm a
young kid dude like I don't know I
didn't know you can't say anything about
movies or whatever it wasn't even a
movie it was a very you know it was a
two thousand dollar pediate whatever and
so after that like I just
um you know I was living in my friend's
uh living room right it was literally
living I was like doing like I was even
I'm already here so I'm just gonna say I
was doing like webcam stuff like hit
naked in front of the webcam in my
friend's living room when he would go to
work oh this was like pre-only fans too
this was like okay
you're like the original only fans
hipster like you were doing it before
everyone was getting made paid like big
bucks on it it was some creepy sights
man it would be like you just be there
naked doing this and then people just
like they'd go to your thing
they tip you or they just keep going and
so I I even tried to Branch out on that
I made a couple Craigslist posts back
when Craigslist used to have like the
the sexy section and I was like looking
for a woman to make love on the webcam
so we can make money hey
man got to pay the rent somehow
those those were treacherous experiences
going to meet
um the people that responded to me on
Craigslist and
so what happened was is I needed a
serious shift because I was doing
incredibly dark comedy where I was like
using really really vile language to try
to break open this void of like people
need to not be so clung
to language to words to being so hurt or
triggered by words that was like the
point of my comedy was trying to trigger
people
to hopefully access something in them
that would allow them to be less
triggered
because words so like you know later in
the deep deep later as of now you know
I'm I I understand that the English
Modern English language that we have now
is actually a magical Labyrinth that has
been created and curated through
thousands of years of magical workings
um so but I didn't know that when I was
young I just knew that there's a bunch
of [__] going on I was trying to
break the void yeah so I was at my truck
at your core you had to throw some rocks
at that you know I got you man this
[__] window and so I was I was I was
at a proverbial bottom to me and uh you
know like I didn't like trying to sell
my body and do all these things so I had
called my mom and I was just talking to
her and she's just like well why don't
you just
go move to Hawaii like you know like
don't you know that we have a friend out
there who has a farm you can go work and
live on his farm it's like no no mother
I did not know that we have somebody
that I know I could go work on them you
never mentioned this 20 years later and
so it was I think a week and a half
after that phone call where I was just I
just decided to
move out to the island and that's really
when I think everything really shifted
for me because
you know
um I went there and I didn't leave for
three years after that point like I was
there and I was I was stuck like a
magnet on a fridge
because the magnet the magnetized energy
that is there the magmatic the volcanic
energy
let's just put it this way oh we were
talking about it on the Vaughn gold
episode right with dolphins and whales
and they have magnified clusters in
their head
as do humans we are attracted to the
magnetic parts of the Earth
and Texas by the way
is incredibly magnetic
um Hollow Caverns salt mines crystal
mines Limestone I found out that Austin
Texas was a huge Limestone Quarry and
limestone is what they would use to
build the [__] pyramids out of
one of the main materials so like the
heavy magnetic draw that it has like
it's a very conductive material used as
a jolly geopolymer so
um we're drawn and attracted to these
places yeah yeah uh uh Tyler Daniels I
don't know if you've ever met Tyler
Daniels he graduated with us as well
um he's down here with it with me as
well he's got his own place and
everything but uh he's become very into
pyramids and like researching that he's
like Red Olive Graham Hancock's books
and stuff
um dude have you watched the new Netflix
uh I I have not watched it yet man yeah
I haven't watched yet it's it's on my
list to watch but I do love Graham
Hancock and I follow some of the stuff I
have not read his books but I always
really enjoy when he's on podcasts and
stuff
dude I've yet to watch the documentary
either and I really really really want
to yeah uh need to because I heard I
heard it's great and when it gets that
much controversial uh feedback
yeah that's good yeah it's funny what's
going on it's hard because I'm not sure
what I think that my view of it through
social media is being painted a certain
way so I'm not really sure what the
truth is so it's hard for me to truly
discern what's going on but it seems
like they're doing this whole
um saying that what Graham has to say is
false or it's like pseudoscience because
they don't want to change like the
mainstream quote-unquote narrative
um and so they're trying to like get it
re-categorized um but again I don't know
like like Liberty saying mainstream
narrative already paints me into this
world of like I don't really know
entirely what I'm talking about
I [__] love that dude you're
incredibly truthful and I love that
about you brother I haven't I haven't
always been man that's something and I
very much pride myself on trying my best
to be truthful it's it's like the only
way to live for me it's I I will be I
have to be 100 truthful now it's I don't
have another option
you're gonna break the patterns that's
growing up that is maturing you know and
one of the hardest things to do is to
one notice the pattern and the two to
break the pattern yeah notice it and not
turn away I think is is a huge thing I
think um you can make a habit of of uh
noticing it and reacting in a different
way or you know creating I mean that's a
lot of how the ego builds its armor
right you know it puts up another wall
noticing it and like okay what do I do
when I notice that thing instead of
being truthful with it I put up this
guard you know so
um okay I'm sorry I derailed you with uh
with this Graham Hancock uh pyramid
Limestone okay so you're you're in
Hawaii Roman you're in Hawaii now you're
magnified to this place
and um
all my dreams came true I mean
Hawaii to me is it was more than
um dreamy beaches
um or you know a vacation
it all it like even going into it I
didn't think I was gonna go have a
vacation like I knew I was gonna go work
I really wanted to work I love work
working makes me happy
um and farming makes me happy you know
when I did when I when I switched my
um focus in school from culinary well I
was like okay well I'm going to regular
College what I'm gonna do I wanted to
get into sustainability and
um Agriculture and you know sustainable
agriculture and all these things so me
going to go work on a farm was a dream
in general and you know so on and so
forth the place was like I was like
great like Hawaii that's awesome
but the Deep penetrating uh
energy that's there is is undeniable
like just having had lived there off and
on for about a decade now
um really has shown me there's something
deeper going on
there spiritually that a lot of people
like because one it's like there's so
many beautiful magnificent islands for
people to go vacation and visit to but
Hawaii is one of the number one world
touristy places like for cross like for
Germans for French for Japanese for
Chinese for Americans everybody in the
world goes to Hawaii that's because it's
one of the seven chakra points of the
planet so people are happily attracted
to it there and I it's almost like you
have to go to it and through it at some
point in your life that energy Vortex
that lives there
to to have to have the fully optimized
experience so I think people will go
there for a vacation and not knowing
that they're actually having a deeper
spiritual lesson at that same time and
people will try to move there for
reasons that they don't know why they
just felt a calling to go move there and
they get there they have crazy
experiences and what we what we call
getting chewed up and spit out then
there's people who go there and they
never leave because they've just been
they've been ingested by Pele and so
you know there's these major workings
these spiritual workings that are
happening and for me I didn't really
notice it until I had left the island
for the first time in the three-year
period and came back to the States moved
back to Portland with a with a woman
started doing that whole thing again
that's when I was able to look back and
be like oh my God like I've completely
shifted everything in my being and I
don't even think I did it to me I think
I think it would happen to me I I didn't
do any of this like I've changed I'm
different and I don't know what I did to
do that I think I was just inhabited by
the by the geographic location you know
it's just crazy it is it's mind-blowing
then okay so so far I feel like the
couple uh instances that you've
mentioned does there feel like
like they're like versions of you like
there's a Roman before this time like
this time in Bellingham when you have
this like out of body experience you
have this like deep profound love for
this person it's like a a cycle of like
wow holy crap I didn't know I could ever
look at this whole experience like the
way I did I'm now a new person I'm now
I'm just cocooned into a new butterfly
and then like you know a couple years
later you end up in Hawaii you have this
new experience you come back to Portland
and you look back and you're like oh my
God I had another like cocooning of a
butterfly is that what's going on is
that is that kind of what you're saying
is that I I think there's so many layers
to us that we
will never unveil all the layers like I
think after you get to this leather
layer there's another layer there that
you need to start working on
um
I don't know if there's ever a point
in this journey in this life and I think
this is what like major magical magical
beings like in history like King Solomon
or these different Alchemists who are
chasing the alchemical Philosopher's
Stone that eternal life here I don't
think there's ever a point a full
Transcendence on this physical plane
I think any time you're going to be here
you're working on a layer and you're
shedding it and I think you can get
through all the layers until you hit
that really really thin point but I
think even when you bust through that
final layer you dissipate as a physical
being and then you enter the spiritual
realm you enter the energetic realm you
enter and across the dimension and you
know I think that's what a lot of like
um these
like metaphorical
allegorical philosophical stories are
talking about when they talk about
Transcendence uh you know I I it's just
yeah I think there's many many many
layers to us but I don't think we're
ever gonna be not peeling back the
layers
right if you're being truthful with
yourself
maybe yeah yeah you might accidentally
be adding more layers which they'll come
off eventually you know it's all your
choice but it's it's your game but uh
yeah I I don't know I I guess I mean I
don't mean to impose that like on your
whole on your whole story so far but so
far that seems like what it is to me is
like it seems like you've been on this
path of kind of like does it feel like
you've been on a path of self-discovery
because I feel like that seems maybe
normal for people like you and I to say
but a lot of people wouldn't look back
at like their their 20s and say oh yeah
I was on a path of self-discovery or
like you know Finding uh finding out
about myself or figuring out about you
know my my place in the universe I'm not
sure that everybody goes through the
same uh Journey more and more are now
that nowadays though
yeah I I don't know man it's
I I kind of weave in and out a lot of
this this concept of like simulation
Theory and you know because a lot of it
makes sense but some of it makes a
little too much sense to where it's like
hmm you know it seems a little a little
like a cop out to kind of say
everything's a simulation
um and then that would really mean that
peop some people are NPCs and to me that
just doesn't feel okay you know like
just because somebody isn't going
through as much of an Awakening
Awakening process of you doesn't mean
you get to consider them a
non-participating character you know I
think that there's just maybe these
people that you know are considered NPCs
they just they haven't you know they're
stuck in maybe a level of like you know
where they they just
who [__] knows man that is it's very
very very difficult uh Waters to tread
and yeah so we can't really talk about
other people we can talk about ourselves
you know we don't feel comfortable to to
call anybody in NPC I think that's rude
and I don't think it's right
well look brother I think you said it
just right you said uh uh you know we're
all on these different levels and I
think that's the way to see it I I
actually have thought a lot about this
NPC talk lately uh because I think like
the younger Generations
um it's like the most normal like it's
really part of their vocabulary nowadays
like this you know I I love this at this
like first first person character energy
like have you heard all this sort of
stuff I think I think there is um some
powerful stuff in that but I think we
should tread carefully um the reason I
say that you just said levels there's
like levels to it
um I feel like when I listen to a lot of
like you know people who would like
meditation teachers or like yoga
teachers or people who have had
near-death experiences or people who are
on some sort of spiritual path or
um you know maybe other people consider
their teachings to be a level of
enlightened you know if you look at
Enlightenment the human path of
Enlightenment as
you know a hundred story building and
and there's just levels and I think that
every person is on a certain level and
like you know some people might think
that they're like up up in the 60s but
they're really like we're all just
probably under 13 or so you know
um but but I think the thing to remember
is
I think thinking about Karma and like
past lives and this sort of thing helps
me remember that maybe this person I'm
talking to maybe Uber Uber driver is
someone I can consider you know an NPC
maybe they're like really low level
interaction with the things that I like
I believe that I'm really interacting
deeply with these same exact subjects
and I know the real truth of them and
like as they're talking you have all
these things of like oh If Only They
knew what I knew and they're just
repeating these things that they have no
idea bro maybe they're just on like the
third level of that story of of all of
our journey to Enlightenment to get to
the level 100 it's just part of being a
human whether you choose to admit it or
or participate in it or not in this
lifetime you're always on that path of
the elevator going up you know on these
floors and some people are just on lower
levels in you and you know maybe in 25
million years
when they're on like the same level
you're on now so so far as you think and
you know they're on level 11. they can
look down and be like oh okay these
people that are NPCs I'm not better than
them I'm not different than them I
haven't like gained anything more
they're just at an earlier stage of
development of me in the karmic cycle of
being
Consciousness yeah yeah existing and I
love it when you know you have an
experience with somebody who you would
never
think that it would have like you like
in the lift car in the Uber car and like
you start to talk to them just to like
kind of like shoot the [__] just to kind
of like poke and prod to see where see
where they're at and you know depending
on your energy for the day how playful
you're gonna be but then you end up just
having this mind-blowing like beautiful
conscious conversation with this
complete stranger almost like it was
like meant to be and you know just
breaks the mold of like you know
everybody playing their part in the
system because here's a good way you
know one of the one of the great ways
somebody explained it on a on
um his name is Michael Juan Susquehanna
Alchemy Susquehanna River
um he's he's on YouTube he does he does
a lot of great stuff
and he's very very energetic too so I
love listening to him but he he
describes something that really stuck
out to me and it was
um
you know kind of breaking the mold of
simulation so we live in a simulation in
a societal simulation now there's a
societal simulation which is society
which has been created you you you have
the Cornerstone of society you have
rules you have Foundation you have money
you have all these rules and parameters
that make the simulated version of
reality which is society but then you
have the cosmic simulation a cosmic code
algorithms that fit in on a mineral
level on a gas level on a bigger
atmospheric Universal level and so it's
almost like we individually are on these
different levels of the building levels
of where we're at but at the same time
Society also since we've created it to
be its own living being is goes through
its levels and then the planet itself is
also working through these different
levels
and so it's fractal it's fractal every
it's just we're all like you know
tenderizing out dude it's it's nuts it's
insane in in all the little fractals are
like I'm the one I'm it all the little
hair follicles are say I am everything
it's all it's me it's me and it's just
completely exploding and moving in in
infinite directions an infinite speed
forever and we're like no it's me
hey do you do you have
um uh I mean I mean I mean so you're
talking in this way in
um did you have what you would consider
I mean through these experiences it
sounds like an A A accumulation of these
sorts of things but did you would you
ever have any sort of like this was my
Spiritual Awakening like there's for
sure Roman this day in Roman like that
afterwards like where you kind of
discovered because even like going back
just a few minutes you're talking about
like the societal structures of who we
are and like the ego self and like
um you know I'm this person with this
job like even that level of like that
initial speed bump of like waking up to
the societal structures of like who you
think yourself to be
um that is like I mean that's a Year's
worth of like work talking through your
ship for a lot of people I mean I feel
like it was for me I feel like that that
alone was a profound Awakening moment
did you have any sort of like
discovering that I've been lucky dude
I've been lucky because I was blessed
with
seeing
the
hmm trying to find the right vocab for
this when I was a kid
I knew the system was broken I knew the
system was broken when I was a child and
I knew it and it kind of hit me in a
weird way I remember going to
Robert Gray Elementary School in
Longview Washington and I was uh
it was just sitting there and like I
just I have this this kind of memory
still it's kind of funny
um it was right before the cookie
Brigade and the cookie Brigade was
that was [__] Tyrant when I was a kid
and I was lashing out for a lot of
reasons and I I didn't quite know why
um but I think a lot of it is is because
I I knew that there was just something
unjust about the system and I knew it
was broken so there could be the cookie
Brigade in sixth grade was
they stop serving cookies to us in
lunchtime
not okay so we banded together a band of
sixth graders and we said what are we
gonna do about this boys what are we
gonna do about this
lack of cookies
Otis Spunkmeyer chocolate chip sunken in
the middle perfectly cooked there's no
way they're taking that away down with
the man
yeah and we we literally got 106th
graders
to say we want cookies cookies we walk
and we stroll through the through the
school and there was this lady that we
uh she wore like the yellow vest you
know I can't remember her name
unfortunately bless her soul we trampled
over her
stop right there we're just like No And
we just keep walking and she like
literally got like fell on the ground in
the middle of 106th graders and uh
you know of course me and two others
after a world did I'm sorry Jesus that
was a dark one and you're just a
comedian so I figured you'd appreciate
it no the dark the dark is the real the
dark is the light man
um
it's so anyways but yeah dude
I don't know if I can I don't know if
there was the point when I ever told
myself I was having a spiritual
awakening
um
I
because life itself is the spiritual
awakening and at some point you just
[__] realize it I do remember there
was a time when I was
having very profound spiritual
experiences
um that I I had like a a spiritual ego
at one point
um with this woman this woman that I was
dating because she kind of rubbed her
energy off on me you know when you're in
a relationship with somebody you kind of
just your tendrils lock up together and
you start to become intertwined and
it is the beauty and it's also it's not
all the beauty but you need to be weary
of how much of other people's energies
are on you and in you and there's
practices and work that you can do to
make sure that it's not happening
um like I'm getting I have a a
clairvoyant that I work with
um if you guys listen to rising from the
ashes and the intro I always will shout
out hurts so buy it so Garden she she
helps me go through a lot a lot of
things like she is trained to
kind of tap into your energy and be like
oh this is not yours let's let's get rid
of that let's pull that out of there and
it took me a while to really settle in
and be like this is actually happening
and whether or not it's it's really
truly happening energetically or it's
just
it's just it's she's taking care of that
in my mental process it still feels
really good to have that work done and
so
it kind of like kind of got lost on the
question there but dude I don't know if
I would ever consider myself having said
like oh I'm going through it right now
but there's just I kind of woke up a
couple years after the fact I think I
was like kind of autopiloting going
through that transition and I really do
think that Hawaii itself the energy the
you know we use these words like energy
Vortex you know things like that when
when there's something it's an umbrella
term
or something so much larger that really
is hard to explain
with with a word because it's a sound
it's a vibration it's an it's a shift
it's something bigger and deeper man so
it's it's hard to explain really the
yeah the Dow that cannot be named is not
the Eternal doubt
um yeah yeah I I I do find I I found
that a lot in this world as I've like
Doven into you know the more spiritual
side of things like all of these words
are just completely like caught way back
um like so many people can if you talk
to me five years ago and you're trying
to use well maybe not five years maybe
like when I was just like a teenager or
early 20s
um you use word like energy and
spiritual like I mean energy I guess
like being a being in the music world
like I would understand what you're
talking about but um I would really put
boundaries up if you start saying words
like spiritual and stuff but there's a
there's definitely like so much that
we're trying to clearly explain that's
right on the edge of our words that
we're like you know like the feeling and
the energy and the and you know and the
like we're just so but the the great
thing is communication is beyond words
like like as you're explaining it to me
even through Zoom even through this
camera and [__] I'm thing I understand
yes yes Roman I get it you know so it's
we're able to say it still right but but
there is it is frustrating like you
almost wish that we could come up with
like a like a a update or a software
update to our language of like
everything about our language is great
but like can we just like let's you know
like when we get emojis we get new
emojis like sometimes we get a hundred
of them like let's just get a bunch more
words like once every year let's just
update our our language so we can at
least a little bit know what we're
talking about and communicate a little
more clearly but yeah that sounds sounds
matrixy too like you just go into your
pod this is like next day you wake up
just 100 more vocab words you're like oh
oh well I mean and neuralink I'm not
sure if you follow any of that with uh
Elon Musk but neural link is going into
human brains in six months
oh like like on the market or they don't
think in the market I think testing I
think legal human trials is six months I
mean I imagine bro they've probably
already done plenty of testing on humans
and monkeys and stuff
um somebody told me they've already
killed a bunch of monkeys but I haven't
looked into it I don't know if that's
true or not yeah I I've been looking
into neural link for quite some time
um
I've had
qualms with Elon Musk for a bit
um
not not in the sense that like what he's
doing but I actually because I'm a
history nerd I [__] love history and
so I looked in the Elon musk's family I
said well let's see what's going on
deeper here
and I'll give you a little a little
background on the musk family
um and uh
it's it's really interesting and what
what a lot of people need to understand
is that it's not that he doesn't work
hard and do all these things but he's he
comes from money and he has had money a
lot of money
big family money that most of us would
never understand this type of money
um so his grandfather was a
um very well-known chiropractor in
Canada
and the late 19th century
and chiropractors were actually like at
high high regard as healers in the
community and it was a really good job
to have if you went to school for
Chiropractic uh chiropractor you were
only working on like people who could
afford such practices and you know
you're you're doing a good job you're
you're an MD you know
um but his grandfather actually started
to get involved in the technocratic
movement and the technocracy
um regime was a part of this
um like half of a secret society
um half of like a business clan that was
starting to get fueled up in the late
19th century in America
well he was a big proponent and the
Canadian technocrats well what happened
is they actually riled up against the
local government the technocrats did and
he actually got kicked out he got
imprisoned and kicked out of Canada
and he had a bunch of money and so he
told his wife he said hey babe
I'm a vigilante baby I'm kicked out of
Canada you want to take this personal
plane and fly around the world and see
the Seven Wonders she's like of course I
do I love you let's do it so they got in
their little plane and they started to
fly around the world
um through there they met all these all
these the right people that they needed
to meet
some of them being the John D
Rockefeller when they were starting the
uh Standard Oil company and the
um
in the in the earliest of the 20th
century Johnny Rockefeller and Henry
Flagler
um who you know you just say that name a
lot of times people are like ears up
Radars up but I can give you the history
on on John the Rockefeller as well and
the Standard Oil company but we won't
get into that right now but they were
friends with them and which meant that
uh the business that they started when
they landed their their final trip they
landed their home in South Africa
where they got into the mining industry
mining minerals in South Africa in the
early 20th century
so when you're friends with John the
Rockefeller and these different other
miners who run the oil oil business and
you're mining rare and special minerals
you're a good person to have uh having a
back pocket there
so may musk Elon musk's mother is born
uh in South Africa and she's beautiful
she's been a model she was a you know
she was hanging out with Charles Manson
and uh she was in the original Charles
Mansion Helter Skelter book before they
took her image out
um she was hanging out in Laurel Canyon
with Bob Dylan and the doors Jim
Morrison like Laurel Canyon was popping
off right at right at May musk
um and and her popularity and fame
started to grow and she became a model
and so on and so forth uh she then
married another uh guy from South Africa
whose family comes from mining so both
of Elon musk's parents come from South
African mining families
[Music]
deep
deep money all puns intended that money
runs deep brother so you you look at
um at uh you know companies like Tesla
and you know how we're getting lithium
and things to make these very specific
High technologically advanced systems
um well it all it all pays homage back
to the ancient mining Roots uh that that
comes from that you know so the access
to these minerals and lifelong access to
um big big Deep Pockets of money and so
I think a lot of what we experience in
the societal simulation is uh a lot of
it's like kind of like planned out in
the sense that like you know like hey
you know
because things take a long time to put
into place when we're talking about big
huge scale and I think the plan to make
oil obsolete has been has been a plan
for over 50 years at the minimum but you
need a way for the the families that
have had this money the families have
access to all of these um these these
fortunes and you know these operations
it takes time for them to be like no
we're going to go oil obsolete but we
need to make sure all of our finances
are set straight ahead of time you know
and to convince the public we need to
you know basically create the create the
story of how it happens you know yeah
yeah I agree with you I think that I'm
with you I uh it's very easy to see with
a little bit of History
to see behind the curtains you know to
like see like oh okay so he's actually
just a pawn and like he's made to be
loved by these people and blah blah it's
frustrating man because I feel like it's
impossible to look I mean you don't have
to look that deeply nowadays into much
to find like oh I tripped over a giant
cable that just put on they put a rug
over it and and you like think I feel
like you know if I was a young person if
I was discovering all this stuff when I
was like 15 or 16 I've I feel like I
would just be you know on the streets
like
um you know like if I can catching
things on fire I don't I don't know it's
it's I don't know dude like the older I
get the more you discover all these
structures that are clearly like all
just
I don't know that our input really even
matters I don't know that like we we
think that I I mean I don't mean to
sound that so nihilistic I understand
that that sounds so nihilistic but I'm
just saying like like sometimes we think
we discover these things and it's like a
Smoking Gun and I feel that way often
but it's almost like I don't know how
else it's gonna be like I don't know
like it's we're so our story is so
entrenched in itself like the the the
truth is so far from how we see reality
that I don't even know if like trying to
backtrack and get back to capital T
truth and what's right is like even
gonna put us where we think it will I I
mean I don't know man you have to work
on your capital T baby that's true
that's all we can do right that's all we
can really do and that's all again we're
supposed to do that's literally actually
a very important part of this whole
thing even functioning properly is we
all have to make our own bed as as old
JP says
is that JP Morgan JP yes JP Morgan no
I'm just kidding uh Jordan Peterson oh
okay I'll vote JP Morgan
had one of these quotes and I was like I
was like oh wow another day from work he
had one quote that was said millionaires
don't have astrologers
billionaires do
oh [__] I've heard this actually I
didn't realize I heard this until you
just reset it okay can we open this door
into astrology I mean so okay you've
also hasn't mentioned that it sounds
like you know a lot about astrology and
like this whole world like can you
I mean I like knowing Scorpio and like
that sort of stuff like a lot of people
you gotta understand your your basic
listener is gonna know like like oh yeah
like horoscopes and I know that I'm like
yeah I guess I'm like a Sagittarius and
like I see it three times a year I look
at my horoscope and it's like oh it kind
of lines up that's cool but otherwise
people don't know about it like yeah I
don't know has this changed your view of
yourself and your life and how you see
the world a lot you know like the more
you learn about it
um looking at my bookshelf I'm like what
can I grab really quickly to kind of
read but um you know
it's
so there are seven sacred Sciences of
antiquity that the people that have you
know
have had money in power for a long time
follow these things so all of our entire
system that we run everything on comes
from uh comes from an old system and
nothing that we have now like I mean
besides like the specific technology
that we have now is new
the systems that we're running upon and
the psychology and philosophies that are
running on are actually incredibly
ancient that's why when you look at the
dollar bill and you look at the back of
it and you see all these like
interesting symbols and things you're
like what is this pyramid with a
floating Capstone and an eye in it like
what is this it's an ancient philosophy
and so one of the seven sacred ancient
philosophies is in fact astrology and
astronomy
so this is incredibly important so when
somebody like JP Morgan
one of the richest influential Bankers
of all of American history
supposedly sunk the Titanic by the way a
fun story won't get into that now but
um when he says something like
millionaires which a lot is money that a
lot of us can't fathom don't have
astrologers but billionaires which is
even more money that we can barely
fathom do they have astrologers what
means is John D is one of the most
famous magicians and occultists of
history in English History he's the
original 007 he's the original
um he created the British intelligence
system he wrote he was making huge birth
charts for the Queen of England Queen
Elizabeth the First when the Renaissance
period started and they they would hire
him to say when is she gonna become
Queen when is the coronation ceremony
and he gets on his chart looks at the
stars you know
observation decks have been funded by
huge huge huge political money Tycho
brahe to create this
um observatory in Sweden on an island to
look at the stars to map the Stars
everything that we actually function on
is a based from astronomy and astrology
and Celestial observations so it's
intertwined within everything that we
are and everything that we do whether
people want to [__] believe it or not
it doesn't matter it is we live in the
celestial map we are here we are a part
of the zodiac we are a part of astrology
we live on a planet you know whether or
not it's geocentric heliocentric it
doesn't matter it is imbued upon our
life and so it has blown my [__] mind
getting into all these things and it
it's taken a long time to to Really
um I I don't know the archetypes of
every every single sign I don't I'm not
an astrologer
um but what I do is I surround myself
with people who are
that's the best way I know how to do it
you know because we all have our skills
so I have another show called Moon
Mysteries that I work specifically with
a Canadian astrologer named Kaylee
burkana
and we just go into the mysteries of the
Moon and she is amazing and she is so
smart dude she knows that every single
archetype of every zodiac sign and you
know through more than that more than
just like a a a two-dimensional circle
on a piece of paper that has an animal
shape and that has a similar no it's
more than that we're talking about these
move and as they move the archetype
changes in every single dimensional
shift that happens it morphs that's why
the second of your birth time is so
important to actually know what
archetype archetypal role that you might
have uh imbued upon your life it is
really really really important because
the second I was born I've never looked
into that I mean you can go minute like
you don't actually don't have to go
second but do you know the the your
birth time
I don't think I ever looked into it call
your mom get you get her to send a
picture of your birthday
it's on your birth certificate get that
um and get a reading from my friend and
she'll blow your mind because
this is what like like JP Morgan was
saying he has an astrologer he looks he
pays somebody to tell him what the space
weather is going to be so he knows when
he should make an investment he knows
what's going to be a dark time for him
he knows what's going to be a light time
for him you know like these like I think
and not as a simulation in the sense
what we were talking about earlier
there's societal simulation and then
there's a Celestial code and I think
that you know at the time that are
inoculated onto this planet that were
imbued with an algorithm or code in
ourselves
that almost has a fulfilled role now and
I think that's part of the layers that
we're shedding off I think has to do
with that true
um
like resonance and
I want to say it again algorithm that is
this that's who we are like why are our
personalities so [__] strong why do
they make a why are our personalities so
unique and different it's a lot of times
it's genetic for sure but and you know
but it's it's Unique and different and
it a lot of the answers are in the
ancient mysteries of astrology yeah I
mean I mean it's really back to that
like dorky you know hair follicle a
little analogy that I use like we just
try to take we try to say what's my
report card now like who am I and how
did I get there and a lot of times we
don't we we forget that we should keep
going back because we play who we are is
like I mean you know people talk about
starseeds like cool go all the way back
then like where you know your little
piece of just space dust bro at some
point and so it all plays a role into
who you are like it's what's it's easy
to like make sense of finding out who
you are of like okay within this you
know 31 years that I've been alive like
what happened to me when I was a kid and
what happened to my parents and what
were their genetics you have this way of
understanding yourself but there's also
like like okay now keep backing it up
and it gets more complicated it gets a
little bit more ethereal it gets more
into that area of like we're saying you
can't exactly always use language you
kind of have to dance around the the
Dance Floor to paint the picture of it
um but but really I mean yeah like like
understanding ourselves
um
yeah it's interesting you know I think
what we do man is
this you mentioned spiritual ego we have
science ego too oh modern our modern
culture has science ego and
um in the second I say that some people
might say like oh well that's because
you're like a spiritual hippie like you
must love religion or I mean it's like
it's like no I like the second you say
even science ego or like you say
anything about science we we defend it
we're like don't you dare and that's
great because science is [__] amazing
in every way and it's literally so I
mean like it's beyond words how amazing
it is but it's not only science it's
science and there's a lot to be learned
in siphoned through like all these other
histories like we're really gonna be so
bold and so arrogant and so pompous that
we're gonna say the only the the only
things that are true is what we've
learned in the last 200 years
like in what what we have learned in the
last 200 years completely you know it's
so much more true and authentic than
anything that all those old books it's
like hold on like you don't think the
other people in all these other cultures
and histories of human civilizations
have had this Wonder that's at the core
of all of our beings of like what am I
what is this you know they've studied it
too in a lot of their their
contemplative answers have led to these
stories and these books in these ways of
seeing the world in late ways of saying
I'm here and that stars up there huh and
you study that for hundreds of thousands
of years and you actually get like
understandings of you know just like
when you like oh it feels good for you
know me to put my wee-wee inside that
girl's thingy and then you start to
notice after hundreds of thousands of
years wow nine months later that's when
that like creature comes out like think
about how how long we had to as humans
like start banging before we realized
that that thing we did that long ago is
what made this baby happen nine months
later like our correlations between time
frames we don't fully understand it
takes us a long time to go oh [__] okay
and then we can start learning about it
but um yeah anyway sorry understanding
the pattern man like we were saying bro
and then when to break it yeah exactly
yeah it's it's helpful to look at your
short-term history for sure but like
there's it's also very helpful to look
at
not only helpful but fascinating and
wonderful and fun to like learn about
astrology and and Alchemy and like what
have other people who have lived in
different time frames than me what did
they learn about what's that one what's
that book you're holding up so Alchemist
handbook freighter albertus
I haven't read that dude because you
were bringing you were talking about um
the past 200 years and like the
separation of Science and God and then
you brought up Alchemy just now and it's
like for people that don't know out and
Alchemy is getting thrown around a lot
right now and so
wait let's go like this
okay it's a chemist handbook yeah oh
it's The Alchemist handbook and what is
what is Al A-L is Allah Allah Allah
l-a-l-e-l is an um old
Hebrew word for God God's chemical help
yes it's the alcohol Alchemist handbook
and
basically we had science and God
intertwined together in philosophy
itself all intertwined together until
there was a huge separation and
about 200 years ago like you were saying
I have a theory
that isn't even that far of a stretch
when you start to study history and
these things but the theory is is that
Alchemy got to a point where they
couldn't not create the Philosopher's
Stone they were transmuting the goal
like a lot of people talk about
transmuting lead into gold yes that's a
thing like that can happen it's happened
people we can do that now gold is
created
so gold was always created in ancient
Egypt and ancient Mayan culture and
ancient Aztec culture gold was
manufactured it was Amalgamated it was
mined for sure but you're not pulling
out
99.9 pure gold out of the land and
you're not pulling out tons of it what
you're doing is you're you're figuring
out how to extract it and then how to
blend it with other metals to make what
we consider to be really good
Amalgamated gold
and so that was a large part of this
like alchemical process but there was
many many parts of this chemical process
many of these legs and what I think
happened is is you know Alchemy was the
science of ancient Egypt
um that's where it began and the
pyramids themselves were in a lot of
ways used for alchemical processes and
um
so but Alchemy was more than just the
science base of like getting into the
still like doing all of these like
different types of practices right it
was more than that it was a
philosophy and it was a it was a part of
going through a mental mental pruning
and turning yourself into the
Philosopher's Stone now some of the most
famous Alchemists in the world like
Saint Germain
um and even later Alchemists like
fulcanelli they have said that they have
never died and they basically have found
the Fountain of Youth the Ponce de Leon
and they have lived forever so I think
my theory is is that we worked up for
thousands of years the alchemical
process and then once we started to get
to a point where Society started to
teeter totter where we were like okay
now everybody's really interested in it
it's not just the higher echelons of
people in power that are starting to do
these things there's way too many
magical people right now we need to
shift this back into it so uh that's
where that's why I think that also the
founding of America was about 200 years
ago too right a little over 200 dread
right you know 1777 so on and so forth
you know really in the 1650s when the
Renaissance period started to happen and
the Protestant Reformation and the
burning of witches thinking about the
witch hunts how many there was there's
claims to be millions of of witches
burned right
that's so much family lineage that will
never be told in the truth if it was
like it'll be skewed like you'd be like
okay my grandma was a part of the the
you know the processing Reformation The
Witch Trials back in the 1600s but
because
sometimes it happens so brutally so fast
a lot of these stories weren't able to
live on like they took really
knowledgeable people who were doing
magical workings and they killed them
and so I think history was written by
its Victors as they say his story
right yeah
so there's a lot like like I mean really
right there what you just said like
really just contemplating think about
all those instances in our history that
like the second that person's Last
Breath leaves their lungs like
everything they know is like if they
haven't passed it along it's gone like I
mean sure there's some sort of
collective unconscious you know there's
something there but we don't know that
information if they weren't able to pass
it on and then so you know the person
standing there holding the knife now
tells their version of that person on
the ground story and and and we act from
that as our truth and that's a dangerous
spot uh um I mean not dangerous spot but
it's a potentially dangerous spot if if
um I'm going to kind of just D Spot it's
what it's what it is yeah I don't know
maybe not good good nor bad it's just
really the truth of the thing I mean
it's it's sad is what it is it is
[__] sad and there is a spiritual war
happening in that sense that like not
all these you know not all these witches
were you know in here concocting poisons
to kill Society you know they were they
were working for their family and they
they saw that there's there was people
that magic is real that's what I've come
to man
after working like all this [__] like
looking up history getting into this I'm
like Magic's real our ancestors knew it
everything but why is it so taboo now
just because we're caught up in our
language man relax with the words relax
with the names and you know exactly
what's going on that's all there is to
it we we actually act I've been thinking
a lot about our language lately and how
we've been reacting and acting like I'm
watching a lot of this Kanye stuff I'm a
huge fan of Kanye um I think our
reaction is to like actually yeah I
think he's so so misunderstood I mean
that's it's a whole can of whoop ass to
even talk about this but
um it's we get so caught up on these
words he said Jew j-e-w he said it like
it's Lord Voldemort bro like get out of
here grow up you know exactly like
what's what's he talking about and I'm
not saying he's got a I'm not saying we
could say whatever we want words are
powerful words are so powerful but
we a lot of times I'm sitting back you
know in the same way that you're telling
your story about um when you're when you
were a kid and you guys are like we want
our cookies and you just get all the 100
kids together to like run over this poor
old lady
um did she survive by the way we should
she did she did I mean she's like she's
in a wheelchair right now listening to
this podcast just like damn you know
but you know a lot of the a lot of the
um
where oh yeah in that same sense you
know I I've also kind of been
I've also kind of always been someone
you know maybe seen our scorpio-ish
nature to
when I'm involved in things I can see
them from the outside I'm able to I
always have an eye a meta eye on the
situation it's just like and you realize
not everybody works that way heightened
intuition
yeah like like so so I've actually used
this to um I described to a therapist
one time when I was talking about like
my childhood like it's like okay we're a
family watching TV you know we're all
together and we're watching TV and I'm
I'm aware the whole time that we're a
family watching it I'm watching us watch
TV you know instead of like my sisters
and my mom my mother and father are like
we're in they're in this story and
they're like laughing about whatever
like they're not thinking about thinking
you know I'm I'm I've always been aware
and so like when adults would like do
like the white lie thing that you tell
you know you don't tell kids the whole
truth you know you give them you know
you you you you you in some senses
you've had the world in in some senses I
don't like that sense but um I was
always so aware like okay so I'm
watching you lie to me but I guess
that's what we do okay and I'm like [__]
okay and I'm always and I've always I
feel like that's how I go why I'm good
at um like I'm a natural introvert in
every way but I'm very good at being an
extrovert because I've always been like
okay so we do that all right like okay
like I'm very well I didn't stop being
aware but I'm like okay I'll do the
games I'm just not really [__] fully
sure why we're doing it this way like if
you're gonna lie to me you're gonna lie
to me I guess but
um
um [__] I forgot exactly what we're what
we're getting on along about
um
well when I question I want a question
for you real quick because I I feel like
I wonder if this is just like a growing
up as a Scorpio type of thing when I was
a kid I had this like
this like movie theater in my head do
you remember Mystery Science Theater
3000 yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah the little
Shadows of the guys down there they're
watching it like talking [__] about the
movie as they're watching it right yeah
I had that in my head for small I think
a two year period
um
and one one instance specific I remember
the Blockbuster that was right over by
the Triangle Mall right where you know
back in Kelso uh and I was in like the
Blockbuster the movie rental place
whatever
and I just remember that there was these
nuns and they would walk in through my
ear and they would go and sit down in
the seats in my head watching what I'm
watching
commenting on what I'm seeing and I I
couldn't have been more than like nine
or ten years old
but that's that observation of thinking
about thinking seeing what you're seeing
from an outside perspective so is that
kind of what what you had too like did
you ever like have a voice inside your
head that was kind of commenting on the
things that were happening yeah almost
in a sense yeah I mean I mean I don't
think mine was as um like playfully
visual I think that mine always had this
um uh
I don't know like like Madness to it or
something I don't know
there wasn't a lot of like playfulness
in mind but yeah it is it's it's a layer
removed like
it's almost
um I mean it's really like just being
overly aware or like consistently aware
um but it is
yeah I I don't know it's almost like a
consistently checking in on your your
story rather than living your story or
something
um I wonder if it's like a so I don't
know if it's like a sometimes I think
it's a trauma thing I thought that it
was a something that I learned from like
having a traumatic childhood I thought
that it was like a disassociated thing
and I learned how to be disassociative
and then use it as a skill
um oh I don't know yeah I don't know if
did you have any like young childhood
before did you have childhood trauma
would you consider yourself someone who
um had oh God significant like like it
that would cause you to as a child put
on Armor or um you know disassociate or
de-personalize any sort of that yeah
absolutely so I um again I'm sorry also
if like you don't have to indulge your
whole personal life I know I get like
very deep so like just feel free to tell
me I'm going too far I'm gonna uh no no
we'll get into it because it kind of
paints paints a good picture I guess too
of like why I was able to see some of
the [__] that was going on as a kid
but
um actually I've had like kind of like a
uh it's it's [__] up and not a lot of
people know it unless you like get to to
know the story but
um
so my dad was 25 and my mom was 15. uh
and he was like a tall good looking
Surfer guy that kind of
was breezing through town and my father
actually has impregnated like
um 11 women and had 11 different
children up and down the West Coast
um he's you know he he grew up like
partying with the chili peppers in
Sublime in Southern California so he was
like surfing skating partying all these
things making his way up and down the
West Coast
but he he wasn't necessarily a predator
in the sense that like you know he raped
my mother because my mother was very
consensually into the situation and they
met when she was 15 but they she didn't
get pregnant until she was 17 right so
it kind of like came through town my mom
dropped out of school as a freshman in
high school
um at 14 15 and uh all of my all her
sisters she has three sisters and
they're all like addicted to different
hard drugs my mother is the only
non-drug addict out of all of them uh
Terry Teresa and Tracy are like either
addicted to like crack meth or you know
one of these other drugs and so they're
still
um for the most part like homeless and
still on hard drugs uh and my mom's just
always been like a rock to them you know
so she saw that at a young age my
grandma was kind of crazy my grandma did
this thing she like stabbed a man uh one
of her boyfriends in Kelso on Cherry
Street she stabbed a man and then she
took the knife to my mom and her sisters
and said if you tell anybody about this
you're dead and then she proceeded to
like beat herself up until the cops came
so she could blame the stabbing of
self-defense so I I my childhood is not
nearly as traumatic as my mom's
childhood but what happened is my mom is
such a is such an angel a legitimate
angel in the sense that like she's had
so she's been such a light in so many
women's lives she's a very very
prominent woman in a lot of
women's lives like she's
selflessly gone to n a for years she was
never a drug addict but she just wanted
to be around people who have had those
experiences because she was felt more
connected to people who were dealing
with drugs and not because that's how
she grew up and so
I saw that growing up too I saw I saw
drug harsh drug abuse as a child to my
blood family members and I kind of like
opened me up because when you start to
like see
gnarly drug abuse
um you know especially as an
introspective Scorpio right like you
start to say like wow this is totally
not right like there's something
completely wrong you're hurt you were so
hurt and I'm so sorry like what can we
do to make you better
um and so all that was happening so on
and so forth but
so my mom got pregnant with the with
this guy he he didn't stick around like
he did zero parenting uh Brad was an
absolutely he actually was Brad by the
way
no no I'm just I just feel like you're
you're like 25 year old Surfer guy who
has 11 kids seems like his name would be
proud
oh my God no that's hilarious yeah no
he's a total [__] brat and uh he had
a kid I have a brother who's six months
younger than me with a different uh mom
same dad so you do the math there six
months he impregnated another chick in
the same town and uh you know but but he
left and what happened was you know
three years later he called my mom and
said he said I want to see Roman like
you know blah blah and she's just like
well uh you know where where have you
been like [__] you you know and he's
just like oh I'm living in Hawaii I'm
living in living in Maui you should
totally have him come out here so he my
mom he convinces my mom to fly me out
there oh wow
I go out there
one week passes two week past three
weeks pass she tries to call him phone's
disconnected
one month passes two months pass
nothing now she's freaking out okay she
is saying you haven't talked to your mom
this whole time this whole time he's not
talking to her I mean you got I'm four
years old dude you know so like
I and so the only thing I remember it
wasn't until I was 15 that I that I
remembered this that
um I remember sitting in a high chair
and there being like a plate of eggs in
front of me in the high chair my face
just getting smushed into the plate of
eggs and I was just like and I look up
and I see this helicopter and my mom
like ascending down a rope
on the helicopter and like I was sitting
in her car you know at 15 and I was like
Mom I keep having these dreams like I've
had this dream repetitively like it's
just crazy I have to tell you about it
she's like oh that's that's not a dream
your dad kidnapped you like oh my God I
was like wait what like that's real the
helicopter like how the [__] that she's
like they were in Mountain my dad was
dating this local Hawaiian woman that
had like property deep out in Hana like
like you you had to [__] basically
take a chopper to it because you're
four-wheel driving the whole time and I
was like what so
um the trauma like I I don't necessarily
think I've like
had the trauma in the sense that like
I don't feel like I've had trauma but
traumatic things have happened
I'm sure that those experiences were a
cataclysmic experience for who you are
today had you not been through the
kidnapping experiences I don't think
that you would be
who you are today I mean obviously you
wouldn't yes you know what I mean like I
think I think I think it's probably a
pretty profound experience like it's
probably pretty like developmental
experience these things like what we do
in reaction to the trauma to these big
things yeah I'm sorry to derail you
again no you're good I love your
insights I'm literally every time you
speak it's beautiful so I love it
brother
um uh and so one of the other crazy
things about this specifically was
so like 16 no 16 or 17 uh
I'm so like I didn't know that he my
father was living in Kelso I didn't know
that he was living in the same town
because I just there was no hearing from
him but he was actually had contacted my
mom
trying to to get a hold of me for years
but she didn't want him to be until he
got sober because he was just he was a
drunk
and he never got sober so when he passed
away
when I was uh
oh that's right I
was eighth grade wow okay yeah it was
eighth grade uh I got kicked out of
school in eighth grade and I got moved
to you know out in Lexington there's
like that Seven Day Adventist Church in
Lexington
so they have a school a very small
school with uh eight eighth graders and
I I went I got kicked out of my school
huge school I was you know friends with
everybody all the things too I got moved
to this private school because I just
kept getting in trouble and uh
I was there and one day you know someone
comes to me and like your father's in
the hospital like with sepsis disease
and I was like what and like I fake
cried I had to fake cry because I didn't
know what to feel because I didn't know
him well that's interesting I so I I
like made myself cry on the couch
so I could get out of going to school
um
because I I didn't [__] care I didn't
care and you're like but I know that the
thing you're supposed to do is is care
like I know that like oh yeah that this
is what you do when when things like
this happen this is what it this is what
society says to do yeah totally do I
totally relate with that because I had a
lot of moments like yeah I guess I'm
gonna I'm gonna cry that's what we do
um connecting to it you know
I love it I love that that's a Scorpio
way man like hold on wait let me see
what are we supposed to do look at
everybody again and sink into it
am I crying have you seen um was it a
North Korea like where they have to uh
there's videos of them crying when their
leader has died and it has to be like a
performative because like you can you
know get murdered and thrown inside a
camp if you aren't bawling your eyes out
to know that yeah yeah because like you
you know you have to be loyal to your
leader like he is God you know he's
everything to you and so if you aren't
devastated the fact that he died then
like clearly the year you know antihim
so yeah there's these videos of like
it's just the whole crowd is just
panning on the crowd of people going
[Music]
and it's and it's dude it goes on
apparently these things go on for like
crazy amounts of time because everyone
is just one-upping each other and it
just becomes this like hours of just
performative like
you know
um
yeah can you imagine I mean it's funny
we do like little versions of that just
to just to fit in Carl Young actually
talks about
um you know he in hit one of his older
books memories dreams and Reflections
where he's like an older man before he
died he talks about when he was younger
he kind of has these instances that
you're recalling where like
um you know like someone said you know
you'll say hey your father died and you
you know you're supposed to cry so you
cry but you kind of know you're faking
it he has Recollections of even like
making himself he you'd physically pass
out he'd faint in like on the playground
and stuff like that and he has these
instances of remembering now that he's
older that he actually kind of did that
to himself like he can recall kind of
the process of it like him doing these
things so I don't know I guess that's
not super correlated but it's very
interesting to look at as we get older
and we retrospect we look back at the
things we did when we were younger with
a little bit of like knowledge and
wisdom we can go huh like that almost
wasn't real what I did like I was
actually crying performatively
and like how many people are doing that
and they're kind of aware they're doing
that in the moment but they're not able
to see that they're doing at the same
time you know that's tricky
I just turned my heater on uh by my feet
so we've got to keep them toasty can you
hear me can you hear the heater no no it
sounds so fun okay oh yeah no yeah I
mean I don't even hear it
um yeah uh are you is it cold where
you're at are you you're Northern
California Northern California in the
mountains uh so high elevation it's it's
chilly it's not cold like I walk outside
naked in the morning in the fog you know
uh dude do you have to yeah I live in an
apartment I miss you know having my dick
out the back door you know what I'm
saying dude I do know what you're saying
because I [__] love it I I'm leaving
this mountain soon though and I'm
driving to Florida in the next I think
on the 23rd I'm gonna be driving to
Florida to go work
damn are you going through Texas
dude if you if you are anywhere near
Austin like within a couple like I mean
I could even I'm three hours from Dallas
oh dude I no I will I'll come to Austin
like I've been great dude have you spent
any time in Austin
I so I went on tour with
um I just I'm looking up my uh
I'm looking up my map route real quick I
went on tour with a band a few years ago
um this band called The Weather Machine
they were a really great folk Indie band
out of Portland and I became really good
friends with one of the guys in uh
we went uh
we went on a cross-country tour and
through that uh
I went to a [__] ton of places one of my
favorite was Montreal
uh I'm dude like the poutine was insane
but we uh the things I remember most
about like traveling is always like the
food you know and Austin we had
breakfast tacos uh because our van
actually broke down we were getting van
work in Austin
uh I can't even tell you where like I
have no idea any I don't even know where
I was like I if I were to go back I
might not even recognize it because it
was just like two or three days of just
intense energy
um of traveling and it says okay go
ahead go ahead sir go ahead
yeah well I mean dude if you do make it
this way we'll find some sort of I mean
I have a couple places that I've found
um I'm I'm pretty loner here so like I
really haven't explored as much as uh
you would imagine like someone like
moving to a place like Austin I really
have not um uh like Doven into the like
food and um you know culture as much as
I should have but there's some places we
can check out and then we could also
like there's so many places for
breakfast tacos and amazing food and
cool environments in Austin it's so
filled up to the brim with amazing
opportunities like that that the day of
we can look up on our phones or drive
around and just see what feels good and
we'll find somewhere like it's one of
those things you you throw a dart and
you land on something just great it's
awesome here I feel like I mean I know
everybody says it but it's I feel like
it's it's just such a cool spot and
everything's pretty damn good here it
seems like dude I mean I I have no
qualms with Austin like I really want to
spend more time there it looks like on
the map it's uh would either put me up
towards Dallas or see San Antonio but it
looks like San Antonio is like an hour
hour and a half from here yeah I'm
definitely gonna
go through that way and then I'll make
sure I stop in Austin because I want to
stay there yeah yeah I was gonna say if
it works out for you and if you need a
place to crash this lovely blue couch
behind me has your name written all over
it my friend oh I see that it's in
graffiti too right there on the side
there it is the next one yeah you know
what I said last night yeah if you look
closely it says the most handsome it's
it's written in graffiti on there I I
said that last night at a gig I got
there and like there's a ton of people
so you check in so they make sure that
they're like okay you're here to work
um and I I tried that I tried yeah it's
under most handsome
[Laughter]
I was the only one laughing in that
situation as it turns out what
what yeah it was too much it was too
much chaos there was too many other
people there was a huge line behind me
it wasn't the time for the jokes you
know I didn't I didn't read the room I
was just trying to fit in my joke so
that's why yeah that's a Scorpio thing
man it's uh we're you know we have these
really great jokes but like you know we
just say them whenever the [__] we want
as opposed to the right time yeah dude I
tried all bro if I could chew it in I'm
gonna shoot it and if I if I'm around if
I'm around a group that I've realized
hasn't heard this specific joke it's
gonna get recycled I'm gonna say it
again I'm gonna say it again just
waiting for that one person just to like
leave the circle for a second who has
heard the joke before just so you can
okay here we go here we go yeah yeah or
sometimes I'll say the joke and then
I'll immediately like just connect with
that person like I know you've heard me
say this joke but like just let it just
like you you break the wall of the joke
by mentioning the joke which
automatically negates it so it's this
whole [__] thing
um uh hey uh okay so I I had a question
about comedy because um I am a huge fan
of Comedy um and I think it's an
interesting conversation but I also
think that a nice question
that was formulating
um for you would be like so say
you're able to like connect with your
like karmic family of you know thousands
of years and you could write a postcard
and it's like it's like hey it's Roman
like hey look I'm one on this lifetime
I've been able to wake up I remembered
my you know my my true self I remember
that I'm here on this karmic cycle to
like experience life and love and this
whole you know thing and I'm just
checking in from Earth like here's how
I'm doing here's what I've learned so
far like as Roman like I don't know does
anything come to mind like I guess your
postcard of life right now what have you
learned what's going on that is such a
deep question
um
I love the visuals too like if I
you're writing a cosmic card to your
ancestors who are just on the other side
of the veil waiting for you yeah uh I
I'd be like
just give me one second here no rush
painted brother
I'm trying not to do the thing where
like I think for a long time about
something that's supposed to be deep and
then I make a joke out of it and then
like do something sarcastic
um but but I think I would say something
along the lines of
that first of all my journey here is not
near
completion
thank you guys for waiting for me I love
you very much
I love love I love my dog
what are dogs
please write back and tell me why dogs
are so connected to us in society and
I think I'm getting closer to
discovering how to
optimize
my true energy and Magic it might be
another decade but I think we're on to
something here
I think I think I'm getting close right
how do you think they would they opened
the mail and they read it what do you
think they're saying they probably just
be like what a [__] turd look at this
dude she's getting close
he has billions more years
[Laughter]
no it's so true man like hey that is
beautiful though you love love and you
love your dog and it's like just the
things that is what it's all about man
it's like what are the things that
remind you to be right here I love that
even before this we were messaging
before this podcast and you're like all
right bro I'll see you in a little bit
I'm gonna go hang out or I'm gonna go
play with my dog and it's like that's
that's exactly what it's about yeah find
some time to play with your dog you know
what else is there to do some people say
that that you know your pet or you're
familiar uh is your eighth chakra
what does that mean to you you're
familiar with your HR to me like so like
a familiar and magical terms like a
witch has a familiar
um or magician or sorcerer they have
this animal entity like uh Salvador Dali
had ant eaters he would go on stage dude
you have to look up videos of how he
would have anteaters on leashes Salvador
Dali kind of hard it's kind of hard dude
it's so hard dude like with this
mustache too you know what a gangster uh
but but what it means is like dude you
you choose like you you choose to have
that eighth chakra that connection point
to this this being you know when you
truly when you're not just white
picketing white picket fencing your life
and you're just like well we've had
three kids it's time to get a dog now
right hon like when you choose I didn't
choose to get a doggie either I did not
choose to get zuji boy
um one of my friends wives brother
had a dog that he couldn't take care of
and they
asked me they're like hey you like
animals right and I was like I mean yeah
yeah
like what kind of question is that of
course
um not a complete POS and so I went over
and you know and then it happened and
then now here we are over a year later
that like there's such a bond that like
I look at him and you know as a Scorpio
I'm like at home I'm like when are you
gonna die like don't don't leave me you
son of a [__] like he's like fully
living and like just but uh he's like
Dad stop talking about my mortality
I'm like I can't help it I love you when
you're gonna die work dude we're
connected to these animals and we choose
that connection because we are so in
love with love like humans are love like
everything that we have down to our core
is a passion it's a heartbeat it's a
feeling and it's the vibration of
unconditional love no matter what when
you separate all the layers that's what
it is and you get in tune with that by
surrounding yourself with the things
that make you feel that make it easy for
you to feel that love you know when
you're with a partner and it's not easy
for you to break down and feel that you
know there's some there's some deeper
things that you need to work on there uh
but if you have a partner where it's
just you're so it's so easy for you just
to respect them for you to respect
yourself for you to take time we're not
feeling anxious and you have the animal
you know like a lot of times it's like
we were talking earlier about uh you
know like having experiences with people
in the different levels and layers that
we're on I think you know you'll be up
here on on level 60 sometimes but one
day you might just have taken the
elevator down to level 24 because your
energy is here you're not you're not
feeling like you want to be nice to
anybody you're feeling like you just
kind of want to like you just [__] it
all I'm gonna start drinking beer it's
you know noon today or whatever
and it's just so it's not it's not easy
to always be at that high level and it's
okay to take the elevator down from
times but having these things surrounded
like create a community it doesn't need
to be a million [__] friends but
create a community of a turtle and a dog
and your guitar and your bananas that
you love or whatever and just just try
to emanate that man and you know kind of
grasp onto it and and just try to be as
much lovey love and breathing helps
breathing practices help a lot
Hallelujah Amen to that
yeah I I think that's what it is dude I
mean it's it's really you know you and I
as like artists or you know um sometimes
I hesitate to call myself a musician but
musicians I know dude I feel that I know
and then when I explain it when I now I
have this caveat of saying I don't call
myself a musician so that sounds even
more it's just a [__] more layers you
know
um
it's all it's all you know just ego
stroking isn't it um yes but it's really
just you know all these things that
we're doing playing with a dog
um um you know getting into flow States
the Flow State you know the athletes
talk about the you know it's it's beyond
runner's high it's it's you're not
thinking about yourself you're not
thinking about your passion you're not
thinking about your your future you're
not thinking about what you need to do
what you have done what you haven't done
um you're just existing in the now it's
really the art of owning a dog is like
if you ask a dog owner
um you know okay so say I'm a little kid
and I'm asking you as a dog owner like
hey what's so what's the point of owning
a dog you'd be like what do you mean
like you don't it's like like the point
isn't to see how old you can get the dog
before he dies like oh I did a good job
of raising a dog it's like no no this is
this is an act of Joy this is love and
that's what it is that's what it's about
it's like
um you know in you partake on that
adventure of of trying you know when
you're petting a dog's belly and you're
laughing and you're talking in doggy
voice you're not thinking about yourself
you're not thinking about your
insecurities that we all have you're not
thinking about how cool you think you
are you're not thinking about how
awesome you look right now petting this
dog's belly you know you're just
existing with a dog and the
um the consistent chattering of the Mind
Falls away so you're just you know in a
state of flow like I was saying you know
just as a musician and a runner and
athlete and all these people are trying
to find their version of flow owning a
dog and being with a dog and loving a
dog and having a dog love you is also a
state of flow this whole thing is all
about play if you can find a way to get
into a state of play whether that's with
another human or a dog or an art form I
think man month older I get the more I
realize that like oh that's what it's
about because you can't take any of it
with you you don't get to take the dog
with you but you can have an experience
with the dog right now
yes yes and do that like just
yeah I think so there's something to
the uh
the dog god connection
oh right you know I've been trying to
find it I'm looking for it still and
it's
you know at least a poem in there
there's a there's definitely a poem in
there uh and maybe maybe that'll be like
the workings that happened oh did you
get a chance to check out the moon last
night after your gig no I didn't I
didn't get out till um probably like 2
30 and then uh I was just tired yeah
what do you be doing
uh last night I was taking down
um a uh like a wrestling show
um so like a aew ACW or whatever it's
not like WWF but it's a basically 14
semi trucks we set it all up they have
like the ring they have like the Antics
the acting the stage the lights whatever
we set up on that I was mainly a
lighting Tech
um yesterday
so oh nice how long have you been doing
that uh man I've been um that's that's
what I do so my my job nowadays is
um I mean I'm technically an audio
engineer I have a degree in that all my
years of DJing that adds a lot of like
work in that and then I'm an audio video
production technician
um in a stage hand so pretty much like
anything to do with Live Events I'm
involved in I get paid to do things at
Live Events and nowadays I'm getting
like I just Epic I'm getting a lot of
good knowledge so I'm you know my my
abilities to do certain roles
um at these shows is expanding so it's
very exciting but yeah last night with
just stagehand stuff
um sometimes I'm making good money and
I'm like the cool audio guy and I'm the
cool guy who knows all the info and then
sometimes I'm just making 18.50 and I'm
carrying heavy ass [__] and it's
humbling and I love it and I get to like
you know meet really cool people and um
you know it's it's been a fun Journey
that's what I do dude that's awesome
what a I mean that's kind of a dream job
for me like I
uh I love
you know what like I said I went on tour
with I've been on tour with two bands
now just being helpful I wasn't part of
the band I was part of the music but I
was you know we load and load out I make
sure boys get their drinks we make sure
we get paid I set up the merge booth and
I have jobs for that bro whole jobs
dude okay do you know jobs
try to come move to Austin and try to
get these gigs you can do it I mean dude
I'm sure you'd be totally fine I mean
you know you got a smart head on your
shoulders you're Pleasant to be around
your uh if you're hard working and
you're not just like you know just
I work with a lot of people who aren't
they just watched other people
struggling and like don't get in there
and help them you know what I mean just
that basic that basic show up and give a
[__] that you apply to any job and
you're gonna be okay that is missing
from a lot of the industry so man yeah
you come on over and if you happen to
know like what an XLR cable is is called
that's helpful too you know yeah I'm
familiar with the cable did cables out
of my [__] ears dude like I'm working
on trying to set up my because my dream
is
um and we're gonna manifest it I'm
taking this year of 2023 to focus on
content and like music research but
here's the deal man I got this epic I
love this this board here this is the uh
Roc you fight yeah dude the ROC 505 MK2
brand new model that just came out last
January uh it was a thousand dollars
very well spent and uh
I wanna I wanna just I want to busk all
over the country and so I'm working on
how I'm going to set my live set up so
dude I probably will definitely be
spending some time in Austin for for
something along those lines dude yeah I
mean yeah like however I can help
however I can show you in like if you
like I said you know I got the couch you
can crash here for a little bit like
dude that would be awesome and also um
you say you like you want to create and
make content and stuff this year like if
there's any collaboration sort of stuff
we can do this this is super awesome man
I'm enjoying reconnecting with you and I
think some stuff and and now that I know
that you like like you sent me some of
your music that I checked out like we
should [__] do some music together
too yeah typical Millennial grown men
things like bro we should we're on a
podcast talking about the music we're
gonna make together I feel like there's
women all around the world making fun of
us in their their flannels and their
tights and they're you know
[Music]
yeah we should dude I've been doing a
lot of uh I feel like my
the DJing side of things and like live
performance
um I'm sharpened on that and I have like
a lot of cool potential ideas on that
and that's you know something we can
talk about too but riding wise man like
if you have any instrumentals or you
need something that needs like spoken
word poetry uh rap like I'm getting
pretty pretty good at spitting these
days so
um just out of fun man that would be
super fun to collect dude I'm supremely
down I
unfortunately I think because the model
of logic that I have is a cracked
version that I got when I bought this
MacBook I bought this MacBook Pro from
somebody just like fully work that
they're like it has Ableton it has logic
it has 3 000 gigabytes you know whatever
and I was like dude [__] yeah like give
me that and uh
but the thing is is like the logic pro
like I've noticed when I share I'm
trying to send like the the stems it's
like kind of hard for me so I'm
interested we should at least try it
um I'm not sure if you want to do like
Google drive or Dropbox or something but
uh I don't know and uh how's the
cross-compatibility between stems on
logic to Ableton
um I think it's figure outable I don't I
think that you do have to export it
differently I mean it's not as easy as
logic it's logic yeah it's not as there
is a process though like we are not the
first um gents to be in this in this
situation so I think we could do a
little redditing and figure it out to be
honest I would love to try me too I
would love to because that yet again is
just like hey I've done that before like
you got that like I got this like let's
so
dude all right cool we'll uh
uh I mean I feel like we got into a lot
of my history maybe next time we'll get
into some of your Journeys in history uh
yeah because I I I want to know yeah man
I know I wish honestly if if I didn't
have to go to this gig I would say this
is going to be a four-hour podcast let's
keep going like I would love to do that
but uh I do have to
um yeah I'm doing like some sort of so
this one is a lighting gig I'm working
for a lighting company it's something
for tick tock no idea what it is I just
show up and I'll probably set up like
some light so people can take selfies
and like it looks cool on camera I don't
know dude there's so many gigs like I
did um for a while what brand ambassador
gigs oh yeah uh which is like a really
great way to make money when you're just
kind of like when you're just doing [__]
on your own you know
um
and in Portland living in Portland where
it was just like there were so many gigs
I just imagine
Austin being the the like the new tech
Hub and just a beautiful growing city
how many gigs there are dude like to
just there's so much work out there it's
got to be yeah it seems it's weird
because it's like hard to
I feel like I haven't been shaking hands
in like something across as many
opportunities as I thought I was like I
thought I would as soon as I got here I
was going to hit the ground running
um but I also like wasn't super applying
myself I was kind of just like sending
some Instagram messages and some emails
and stuff like that but
um it is a thing like once you it's like
you're on these job sites and like I
said you you prove that you're hard
working and you're not like a total
knucklehead and you're not like trying
to escape to smoke a cigarette every 38
minutes
um you know like people at the end of
the gig are like hey uh so you work in
Austin often like you know there's a
handshake exchange that you seem to bump
into and I'm doing it's been happening
more and more for me lately as I've been
you know doing the gig so I think there
is a few hours a few months of
groundwork but uh yeah I think that all
you got to do is just show up and work
hard meet people shake hands and you'll
have the opportunities I think that's
really just the nature of the Beast
it's work it's work and it's like do you
want to work on work or do you want to
work on yourself do you want how many
how many jobs do you want to apply
yourself to or do you want to just shut
it all off and go to bed
yeah I mean it's yeah it's uh I saw a
YouTube video the other day that the
title was I didn't even watch the video
it was I could go to sleep or I could
create my magnum opus
oh my God that is so [__] I can't
dude I struggle with that every night
I'm like every night like do I even
deserve to go to sleep have I
accomplished anything today
like it's just I can sometimes you just
put yourself on this pedestal of like
what you should have done that day to
accomplish like your your wildest dreams
you know it's it's I mean it's it is
true though and it is good to have that
contemplation because it's like as much
as the self-care and the sleeping is
good it's like a lot of times the only
time you're gonna create that Banger to
one of the coolest songs I ever made was
when there was some really annoying
[__] in the living room partying all
[__] night I couldn't sleep because
they were just partying and all and so I
was just like whatever grabbed it I was
up till 3am making these like sounds I'd
never made before and I was just like
maybe there is something to this really
late night thing because I just love
sleep so much you know but it's it is it
takes that mental effort that mental
work to get up and get over get over
ourselves you know how dare you think
you get to choose all the time
[Laughter]
yeah yeah no I'm totally with you but
sometimes I would that's that is is
something that every artist can relate
to though is
sometimes when you catch one in the net
you you seriously go like oh like this
one's dope like you kind of understand
right like sometimes you'll get like
your first few lines in or you kind of
like get your first verse in or whatever
it is that you're writing you get your
you know your drum pattern down and
you're like okay this is sick this is
really sick like I gotta like put my
phone on do not disturb and like make
sure I catch this make sure that I'm
listening or I'm not gonna hear this all
the way you know because it'll float
away you can't just like you don't it's
not like okay well my office hours are I
remember it's like if you catch an idea
you don't get to just cool I caught that
and I wrote the first line down I'll
open that up tomorrow morning like you
you know no no you know you're not going
to no man you gotta you gotta follow the
coattails of it that's how it goes yeah
[Music]
um
yeah uh bro so
yeah I I would love to do this again
um yeah and then I I can I can do less
yammering and you could ask me about my
background and stuff too but uh I do
appreciate you allowing me to peel back
some of your your layers I think you're
such like just a like not only just a
fascinating person but just like a
um a sweet and wonderful person to be
around it's like something I always
remember
um about our interactions before
um and I think that anybody who knows
you is probably in agreeance with that
you're just a wonderful person to be
around so it's cool to kind of get to
see behind the curtain of Roman and and
explain a little bit about you man dude
yeah I mean you uh uh and my eyes
growing up you were uh you know you were
cool as [__] man you had the you had the
sick van
uh you know one of the first tattoos uh
of the crew you know uh if I'm not
mistaken right and then you know the
sick job at the mall and the skate shop
yeah it's like it was I was just like
dude Jake's got it all man I [__]
love that guy yeah that's that's 16 you
know I got I got my van it's got a sound
system in it I've got more than one job
I felt cool I felt pretty cool
yeah I wasn't that cool but I felt
pretty cool no you were man you were
dude like our friend group was very
unique uh interesting I was so glad to
to like kind of become a part of that
friend group when we went to Kelso oh
man dude
the cool people that we've met that like
you wouldn't I think about that actually
with
um now that I've been away from our
hometown for a while you get some cool
retrospective you know perceptions of
like how you saw it when you were
growing up and the things that you got
to see being someone who's from that
Hometown like Austin for example every
you know you talk about Austin and talk
about these places
he
when I'm talking to someone who was born
and raised here who grew up here and
they you know to get to middle school
they cut through this path through the
woods you know to go by this building
and like they have all these intricate
visions and views of not only people but
like the town that you just can't get as
a not only a tourist but even if you
move there as an older person you know
and so um
I don't know I think that me trying to
like understand Austin as an outsider
and like try to get as much as I can
about the essence of about the qualia of
of the place by stories and by people
telling me about their experiences with
them
um you you just can't get the whole
thing from having that you know it's
different than having that lived
experience so like when you really look
back at like wow our lived experience
like what do we like it really is a cool
place that we grew up in like like as
easy as it is to maybe like have a view
of people who haven't like been out of
Cowlitz County and maybe the like maybe
it's a little more narrow than some
places in some ways
um but there's also like the way that
some of these people see the world is
just so cool the way that some of these
people have made me laugh from the core
of my belly is just like unlike any
other place you know the situations that
I've been able to be a part of in these
friend groups and stuff
um God I mean yeah just like just
flashing your memory back to all the
cool people we've met at parties or
skate parks or after school or at the
mall or all these places there's
I don't know man there's some cool ass
people and it's a pleasure to know who
asked people that's for sure it is and
that's that's why it's just like we need
to keep traveling we need to keep going
we need to keep cruising and it just
never stop man you know like we're out
here doing it and we we're never gonna
stop doing it we just gotta like keep
meeting cool people keep the love
flowing and growing yeah yeah stop stop
taking your report cards stop saying
this is who I am now and this is exactly
who I am and I learned this little bit
of history and I'll be this person
forever it's like nope every single day
meet new people explore new places of
yourself and other people in other parts
places of the world and you never know
who you're going to be on the other side
of that day you know yes yeah like
a lot of things is like just allowing
yourself to be open it's like that thing
we're talking about with like the late
night like it's just be open to like
whatever
Baseline you're gonna put down whatever
key you decide to go and
be open to the fact that you might go
out and have a terrible experience at
the store but right after that you might
meet this like really cool person in the
parking lot or nothing happens and it's
all [__] good you know but you're
just knowing that you're open to it and
maybe telling yourself you're gonna meet
somebody and then forgetting that you
said that in the beginning of the day
and then at the end of the day you're
like holy [__] I did meet somebody super
[__] cool today like you're just open
man it's so tough beautiful it's [__]
beautiful man this has been great you're
[__] great you're great too man okay
well uh let's wrap it up will you make
sure that everybody listening still
knows where to find you where to find
your podcast where to communicate with
you where to listen to your next podcast
when does it drop like everything that
they can do to follow you from here on
out oh thank you thank you thank you
thank you like a like a Shameless plug
um there are three there are three
podcasts
one is the baby that's the the
stronghold that's rising from the ashes
it's a History Podcast you guys have uh
a bunch to look look at for our past
episodes but to look forward we are
getting into serpent symbolism in the
month of January with different um
authors and then February and a few
months after that will be ancient
Ireland and we're talking to authors and
researchers about the ancient mysteries
of Ireland and the truth about
leprechauns and the truth about the FAE
and the connections to Ireland and
ancient Egypt and ancient India and
there's a huge huge huge mysterious
Rabbit Hole there so we're really
looking forward to that
um you guys should check out Moon
Mysteries is a podcast that I do with an
astrologer where we have two only two
episodes a month one of the episodes we
focus on like the moon cycles of that
month so what the new Moon's gonna be
you know in Sagittarius what it's going
to be in the next sign and then we each
read articles that are either folklore
about
um ancient deities of the moon or
whatever just like really fun
articles questioning the mysteries of
the Moon
um and then the other episode of the
month is an interview based with like
the authors there's actually like so
many different books that are literally
called Mysteries of the moon or Moon
Mysteries so that's fun and then the
other final show
um which we are most recent episode was
on Austin Texas it's called esoteric
America where we dive into
[Music]
some of the deeper history of random
towns and cities
and we invite people onto the show to
tell us about their town they don't have
to be authors they don't have to be
researchers we would actually prefer it
if it's just normal people yeah and they
dig into the histories of their town and
tell us about it yeah it's so fun I love
this idea it's such a cool idea dude I
mean if you if you want to do it I'd
love to have you on if you want to talk
because we're talking awesome all this
month so if you feel inclined to look up
some some weird things it's a here's the
cool thing there's no land like whatever
it is dude like whatever you find you
know how rabbit holes work on the
internet you just start going down it
you're like oh [__]
yeah 100 cool yeah no maybe I'll check
into stuff I will say uh on your on your
rising from the ashes podcast
um the hair on the back of my neck
tingles when you say you're focusing on
like serpent related things
um I have I have a lot of um I study a
lot about like Kundalini Awakenings in
in these sorts of things I'm actually
fairly certain that I have had a
Kundalini Awakening a few years back so
I would love to uh I would love to talk
about that I have I have some books that
I can send you actually
um yeah I would love we could talk about
that later but yeah so uh maybe maybe
throw me in into that uh January mix of
serpent talk I'm super down let's plan
on that actually let's plan on talking
Kundalini Spirit uh spirit symbolism
serpent symbolism dude like
last night we were looking up something
and we ended up going down the rabbit
hole of house snake's mate all snakes
have sex and they do they do it by
connecting their tails
is a small opening like the genitals of
both the male and the female are like
inside an opening so when you see like
the caduceus staff of Hermes
of how like two snakes twisted around a
staff
like that that's what happens like and
then they coil around each other and
they tense up and it's just like maybe
start making me think about a lot of
things like this strange like tendency
we have to like choke each other during
sex
is similar to like how snakes coil up
and wrap around each other and they make
compression on each other when they're
making love with each other yeah
constriction of the breath and
everything yeah yeah isn't that isn't
that crazy I was like I think we're if
we're playing on touching on something
that's uh outside of our of our human
cells when we when we do that because
it's a very very big tendency that
people
love like a lot of people yeah yeah Heat
at the moment yeah like even if you act
like you don't love that stuff Heat of
the Moment if it starts happening it's
like yeah what's up yeah exactly exactly
so it's just like it's that's Kundalini
man if we're just yeah so I'd love to
talk about it dude we can keep going
forever man I know yeah putting a bow on
it right here wonderful all right Roman
well man thank you so much um yeah
everybody please check out Roman's
podcast
um are you are you active on social
media are you pretty active on Facebook
do you like people to follow you on
there or anything or oh so yeah hit me
up on Facebook that's just Roman Merrell
um
but if you guys do the the one social
media I do do a lot of doo doo uh dookie
in telegram uh telegram is a group
messaging platform that's like it has
the compa the user friendly
compatibility that Facebook and
Instagram has
um but it's like
so I'm gonna I sent you this on Facebook
Messenger while we're chatting I'm in
like a group of podcasters like the
one-on-one podcast the interverse
podcast us like there's uh Chaney and
project Cheney like there's a bunch of
really cool podcasts and we'll do group
shows commonly but we all have our own
telegram channels and
telegram is awesome
um I hope I if you don't have telegram
Jake please get on it dude like I'll
join you to our uh rfta group we have
like 200 people on there that's in a
group chat and like everybody's just
sharing books music articles all this
stuff so it's really amazing and
overwhelming at the same time
[Laughter]
I would love to uh yeah please send them
away I do actually have I think one
friend just maybe I do have the app
telegram I have a friend who has like a
small like 15 person uh men's chat that
um he had invited me to to be be a part
of and I think that is on telegram
actually so but yeah um yeah do
definitely send me that uh or I will
check into that link that you had
already sent me so noise
nice all right well hey everybody
listening love yourselves if you haven't
drank uh you know a pretty good amount
of water today it's like what are you
doing get it together get your life
together get between the lines like you
know it's sober up man drink some water
stretch love yourself
um
um yeah what else like it dance dance
and play with your dog you know yes
you're never gonna drive anywhere so so
play with your dog put your phone away
and and love yourself all right Roman
man I'll talk to you soon buddy it's so
much love I hope you have a good rest of
your day buddy you brother thanks thank
you for the chat brother bye
[Music]
knowledge is power
reality is
[Music]